Arthur W. Row Papers MS090
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Arthur W. Row Papers
1864 -- 1938
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Row, Arthur William
MS090
9 Linear Feet 18 boxes
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Custodial History
Around 2003, this artificial collection of Row papers was created pulling items from the Henry Y. Porter, Max Tennis and the Frank E. Fowle papers. An inventory of his collection exists, and while most of the items have been accounted for according to Row's inventory, it should be understood that some of the collection may still be mixed amongst Porter's papers particularly. Furthermore, some of his papers can also be found at the Billy Rose Theatre Collection in New York Public Library for the Performing Arts.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the correspondence and published works of Arthur W. Row; prepublication material including annotated drafts; and theater-related books, photographs, ephemera and objects he collected. Ephemera include theater programs, scrapbooks, and clippings. Objects include stage costumes and jewelry.
Related Materials
More Arthur Row papers can be found at the Billy Rose Theatre Collection, the contents of which are listed on their website.
Biographical / Historical
Arthur William Row (1878-1961) was an actor, writer and director. Row was born in Montreal, Canada, on June 12 1878, and moved with his family to Boston, Massachusetts in 1893. Beginning at Tufts as a member of the class of 1901, he only attended Tufts in 1897-98 as a special student. He was a member of the Theta Delta Chi Fraternity.
While at Tufts, he began writing dramatic criticism for Boston area news papers and started to act as an extra with Richard Mansfield in 'The Devil's Disciple.' He then joined the Castle Square Theatre stock company in 1898. Row wrote for various magazines including Harper's, Bellman Magazine, and Poet Lore; he was the press representative for Sarah Bernhardt's 1916 American tour about whom he wrote a series and then a book, 'Sarah The Divine.' "In 1919 he was a founder and director of the Afternoon Theatre where he produced Maurice Maeterlinck's Aglavaine and Selysette with Eva Le Gallienne and Clare Eames, Moliere's The School for Scandal and Oscar Wilde's Lady Windermere's Fan."He wrote many laudatory accounts of actors as well as theatrical subjects, and played supporting roles for most of his stage life.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Greater Boston arts; Alumni collections; Row, Arthur W.
- Arthur W. Row letters, periodicals, photographs and books, 1864 -- 1938; 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001; 8.4 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes some letters concerning props rental for various productions as well as playbills from its productions. It includes many of the rejection letters for Row's biography of Sarah Bernhardt, which was eventually published in 1957. Also in the collection are various prepublication materials including notes for the Bernhardt book and annotated drafts of magazine articles by Arthur Row. Includes cards and letters from such figures as David Belasco, Willa Cather, John Drew, Raymond Massey and Ellen Terry. Plays found in box two were probably directed or adapted by him. Box three includes periodicals for which Row has written, books he owned, and a comprehensive inventory list of his collection. Box four includes a comprehensive collection of production photographs from Morris Gest's production of The Miracle, and pictures of Row himself. All in alphabetical order according to his inventory, or by file. Box five includes typed manuscript pages of "The Divine Sarah," poems, and other musings. Sorted into folders, but not organized. Box eighteen includes periodicals for which Row has written, books he owned, and a comprehensive inventory list of his collection.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged as found.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Letters to Row, alphabetized by sender, 1913 -- 1933; MS090.001.001
    Includes cards and letters from such figures as David Belasco, Willa Cather, John Drew, Raymond Massey and Ellen Terry.
    Row, A.W.
    - Index cards to letters A-Y, MS090.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    - Letters - A, 1920 -- 1927; MS090.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
      12 letters.
    - Letters - B, 1920 -- 1931; MS090.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
      11 letters, 1 card.
    - Letters - C, 1923 -- 1930; MS090.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
      21 letters.
    - Letters - D, 1921 -- 1930; MS090.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
      2 letters.
    - Letters - E, 1924 -- 1927; MS090.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
    - Letters - F, 1915 -- 1928; MS090.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
      23 letters.
    - Letters - G, 1923 -- 1925; MS090.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
      4 letters.
    - Letters - H, 1913 -- 1931; MS090.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
      16 letters.
    - Letters - I-J, 1928; MS090.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
      1 letter under J. No letters under I.
    - Letters - K, 1923 -- 1933; MS090.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
      7 letters.
    - Letters - L, 1917 -- 1931; MS090.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
      10 letters.
    - Letters - M, 1919 -- 1932; MS090.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
    - Letters - N-O, 1927 -- 1930; MS090.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
      7 letters under O. No letters under N.
    - Letters - P, 1923 -- 1928; MS090.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
      5 letters.
    - Letters - Q-R, 1924; MS090.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
      7 letters under R. No letters under Q.
    - Letters - S, 1930 -- 1933; MS090.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
    - Letters - T, 1916 -- 1929; MS090.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
    - Letters - U-W, 1920 -- 1928; MS090.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
      16 letters under W. No letters under U and V.
    - Letters - Y, 1923 -- 1929; MS090.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
      6 letters.
  - Letters, programs, plays and published writings of AWR, 1915 -- 1935; MS090.001.002
    Plays were probably directed or adapted by him.
    - Published materials of AWR9, 1923 -- 1933; MS090.001.002.00001; Row, A.W. (Box 2)
    - Manuscript of play, Winter, 1933; MS090.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
    - Manuscript of play, The School for Scandal, act III, MS090.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
    - Manuscript of play, Therese Raquin, MS090.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
    - Manuscript of play, The Fourth Mrs. Will, MS090.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
    - Manuscript of play, Aglevaine and Selysette, MS090.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
    - Writings on Kate Douglas Wiggins, MS090.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
      Writings on her by AWR and clippings on "Timothy's Quest". No Date Available
    - Randolf S. Churchill, notes, 1930; MS090.001.002.00008; Row, A.W. (Box 2)
      Interview by AWR with R.S. Churchill.
    - Letters to AWR regarding returned manuscripts etc., 1922 -- 1930; MS090.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
      Mostly rejection letters from places with whom he wanted to publish.
    - Afternoon Theatre, letters, programs, reviews and press notices, 1923; MS090.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
      Date is approximate
    - Theatre programs and press notices of plays in which AWR appeared or directed, 1930; MS090.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
      Clippings included as well.
    - New York and Boston Theatre programs, 1915 -- 1933; MS090.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
      Various programs from productions including Provincetown Players, The Alvin Theatre and The Neigborhood Playhouse.
    - Souvenir Programes, 1928 -- 1935; MS090.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
      The Player's seventh annual revival of The Beaux Stratagem; The Player's ninth annual revival of Milestones and The Little Father of the Wilderness; Actors' Equity Fund Benefit.
    - Clippings, 1922 -- 1923; MS090.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
      Mostly clippings about Sarah Bernhardt
  - Row's periodicals and inventory of collection, 1917 -- 1930; MS090.001.003
    Includes periodicals for which Row has written, books he owned, and a comprehensive inventory list of his collection.
    - Inventory Arthur William Row collection and speech notes, MS090.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
    - The Spectator, May/June, 1917; MS090.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
    - Punch, November, 1923; MS090.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
    - Equity, 1922 -- 1930; MS090.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
      Includes issues from 1922/23/24/30
    - The Living Age, Sat. October 11, 1924; MS090.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
    - The Stratford Magazine, January, 1928; MS090.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
    - The Nation, Wed. August 8, 1928; MS090.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
    - The Younger Set, January, 1924; MS090.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
    - The Younger Set, March, 1924; MS090.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
    - The Younger Set, October, 1923; MS090.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
    - The Younger Set, December, 1923; MS090.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
    - The Greenwich Village Spectator, 1917 -- 1918; MS090.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
      Monthly periodical. Missing December 1917.
    - The Drama, 1925 -- 1928; MS090.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
    - Clipping, Hedda Gabler, 1928; MS090.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
      A letter to the editor from Mary Shaw regarding Eva Le Gallienne's interpretation of Hedda Gabler.
    - Psychology, 1926; MS090.001.003.00015 (Box 3)
    - Theatre Magazine, 1926; MS090.001.003.00016 (Box 3)
    - The Dial, 1928; MS090.001.003.00017 (Box 3)
    - Harpers Magazine, 1929; MS090.001.003.00018 (Box 3)
    - Poet's Lore, Summer, 1929; MS090.001.003.00019 (Box 3)
    - The Shield, 1924; MS090.001.003.00020 (Box 3)
      Volume 40 no. 3. Published by Theta Delta Chi.
    - The Shield, 1927; MS090.001.003.00021 (Box 3)
      Volume 43 no. 4. Published by Theta Delta Chi.
    - The Living Age, 1925; MS090.001.003.00022 (Box 3)
  - Various photographs of theatrical personalities and production photographs, some autographed, 1913 -- 1938; MS090.001.004
    Includes a comprehensive collection of production photographs from Morris Gest's production of The Miracle, and pictures of Row himself. All in alphabetical order according to his inventory, or by file.
    - Photos of Arthur Row, 1916 -- 1938; MS090.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
      Some autographed.
    - Kate Douglas Wiggins, photos of "Timothy's Quest" and autographed portrait, 1913 -- 1936; MS090.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
      Production photos of "Timothy's Quest" produced 1936 and autographed photo of KDW to AWR.
    - Sidney Blackmer, photo, 1919; MS090.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
      Autographed and dated 1919, previously framed.
    - Print of Glenn Hunter, MS090.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
      Previously framed. Includes notes by AWR on it being hung in the Hudson Theatre, New York. No Date Available
    - Photos of other actors and actresses, 1913; MS090.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
      Includes Julia Marlowe as Lady Macbeth.
    - Photos from inventory, A-Co, 1920; MS090.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
    - Photos from inventory, Du-Mar, 1925; MS090.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
    - Photos from inventory, Mas-Wal, 1920 -- 1930; MS090.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
    - Photos from inventory, We-Yu, 1920 -- 1930; MS090.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
    - The Miracle production photos, 1925; MS090.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
      Includes production photos and images of Gest and Max Reinhardt.
    - Unidentified photos, MS090.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Manuscripts of AWR's writings, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005
    Includes typed manuscript pages of "The Divine Sarah," poems, and other musings. Sorted into folders, but not organized.
    - Manuscript pages on the Barrymores, January 24, 1930; MS090.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript pages on the Barrymores, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript pages on the Barrymores, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript pages headed "The Legend of the Barrymores", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript pages on the Barrymores, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript pages on the Barrymores, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00006 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript in notebook on Sarah Bernhardt, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00007 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript pages on the Barrymores, Sarah Bernhardt, one page headed "The Suicide Complex", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00008 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript notes on appointments, production budget, notes copied from "Life's Ebb and Flow," by Frances, Countess of Warwick, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00009 (Box 5)
    - Typescript pages on Sarah Bernhardt, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00010 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript of Strindberg's writings on the Intimate Theatre, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00011 (Box 5)
    - Carbon of foreword, first pages of "Sarah the Divine", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00012 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript notes on Immigrants' Memorial, carbon of letter to Morris Gest, February 10, 1930; MS090.001.005.00013 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript and typescript pages on the Barrymores, draft of preface for Barrymore book, notes on Mrs. Patrick Campbell, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00014 (Box 5)
    - Hammond typewriter info, 1914; MS090.001.005.00015 (Box 5)
    - Blank Tuftonian award certificates, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00016 (Box 5)
    - Blank Senior Dramatic Society initiation certificates, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00017 (Box 5)
    - Blank Ivy Society admission certificates, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00018 (Box 5)
    - Sophomore dicta on Freshman behavior, annotated poster, 1904; MS090.001.005.00019 (Box 5)
    - Typescript on Chicago production of "The School for Scandal", 1925; MS090.001.005.00020 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript pages on Sarah Bernhardt, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00021 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript pages on Sarah Bernhardt, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00022 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript pages on Sarah Bernhardt, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00023 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript pages on Sarah Bernhardt, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00024 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript page on Sarah Bernhard in the year 1913, MS090.001.005.00025 (Box 5)
    - Unidentified manuscript page (speech from play?) and typescript page of jokes, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00026 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript and annotated typescript pages on Sarah Bernhardt, unidentified notes, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00027 (Box 5)
    - Two letters to the editor of The Younger Set, September, 1923; MS090.001.005.00028 (Box 5)
    - Envelope of manuscript notes on Sarah Bernhardt and publicity brochures for the Carolina Players, 1924; MS090.001.005.00029 (Box 5)
    - Inventory notes on collection, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00030 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript pages on Lou Tellegen, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00031 (Box 5)
    - Unidentified manuscript pages for articles and annotated typescript page of fiction headed "Easy Money", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00032 (Box 5)
    - One typescript page on Duse, annotated typescript of piece called "Acting in Chautauqua", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00033 (Box 5)
    - Typescript of review of book on Duse, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00034 (Box 5)
    - Typescript of "The Legend of the Barrymores", copy of typescript of "The Legend of the Barrymores" identified by hand as "copy of revised text", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00035 (Box 5)
    - Typescript pages headed "Memories of Sarah Bernhardt,", "People Who Have Died for Sarah Bernhardt", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00036 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript pages headed "People Who Have Died for Sarah Bernhardt", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00037 (Box 5)
    - Article from Harper's Bazar, "Charm" by Sarah Bernhardt, November, 1917, Typescript (slightly different) version of the same article, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00038 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript pages, "Biography of Sarah Bernhardt, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00039 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript, "'The Book of Job' as a Theatrical Venture", 1919; MS090.001.005.00040 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript pages, "Closeups and Forecasts,", 1927; MS090.001.005.00041 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript and typescript pages, "Mrs. Patrick Campbell: Lecturer-Actress-Personality and Wit", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00042 (Box 5)
    - Typescript of interview with Noel Coward, identified by hand as "unpublished interview", 1925; MS090.001.005.00043 (Box 5)
    - Typescript headed "'My Struggles to be a Repertoire Actress' as Related by Jane Cowl to Arthur William Row", 1926; MS090.001.005.00044 (Box 5)
    - Typescript of obituary piece on Florence Deshon, with her name as handwritten heading, 1922; MS090.001.005.00045 (Box 5)
    - Typescript pages headed "Duse - the Enigma" and "The Return of Duse", 1923; MS090.001.005.00046 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript and typescript copy headed "What Eleanora Duse Means to Me", c. 1923, annotated typescript has handwritten note, "This is sold to the Metropolitan comes out in May no.", MS090.001.005.00047 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript of obituary of Clare Eames, annotated typescript headed "Every Knock a Boost", 1922 -- 1930; MS090.001.005.00048 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript headed "The Man Behind the Moscow Players, Morris Gest", 1923; MS090.001.005.00049 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript headed "The Legend of Morris Gest, the Man Behind the Moscow Players," annotated typescript headed "Comstock and Gest's Season Requires an Index to keep Track of World Famous Names", 1923 -- 1924; MS090.001.005.00050 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript headed "Glands vs. Morality,", 1927; MS090.001.005.00051 (Box 5)
    - Typescript headed "Great Moments in Great Acting", Poet Lore, May-June, 1918; MS090.001.005.00052 (Box 5)
    - Typescript headed "Louise Closser Hale,", 1926; MS090.001.005.00053 (Box 5)
    - Typescript headed "Emily Wakeman Hartley - Manageress," clipped article, "Actress Manages Tryout Theatre," Equity, October, 1926; MS090.001.005.00054 (Box 5)
    - Two annotated typescript drafts headed "Houdini and Sarah Bernhardt,", 1924; MS090.001.005.00055 (Box 5)
    - Typescript on Glenn Hunter headed "Creator of the American Boy and his 'Orchard Theatre', 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00056 (Box 5)
    - Two copies of typescript headed "I Go on Tour with 'The Miracle'", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00057 (Box 5)
    - Typescript pages headed "Is America Starving?", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00058 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript headed "A Kate Douglas Wiggin Garden Party," published in Poet Lore, no date given, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00059 (Box 5)
    - New York Times clipping, obituary of Paul Kester, manuscript notes on Kester, 1933; MS090.001.005.00060 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript of "A Matter of Beauty, a Talk with Helena Rubenstein", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00061 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript draft, typescript headed "Senorita Raquel Meller," Psychology Magazine, 1926; MS090.001.005.00062 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript of a letter to the dramatic editor of the New York Times on Sarah Bernhardt as L'Aiglon, pencil notes on reverse, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00063 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript headed "The Philosophy of Jiu-Jitsu", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00064 (Box 5)
    - Typescript headed "Psychology in Beauty", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00065 (Box 5)
    - Typescript headed "Arthur William Row," three typescript copies headed "A Many-Sided Specialist: Actor-Producer-Author Is Arthur Wiliam Row", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00066 (Box 5)
    - Annotated manuscript headed "Lillian Russell: Her Place in the Sun", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00067 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript and one manuscript page headed "The Duchess of Rutland", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00068 (Box 5)
      The Duchess of Rutland was the mother of Lady Diana Manners, who played in Max Reinhardt's The Miracle
    - Annotated typescript headed "Francis Sagerson: a Physician of the Soul", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00069 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript headed "Anthony J. Sansone: an Interesting Youth," second annotated typescript copy headed "The Triumph of Anthony J. Sansone: an Interesting Youth", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00070 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript of review of "Scarlet Sister Mary,", 1930; MS090.001.005.00071 (Box 5)
    - Typescript headed "Mary Shaw: the Lady of the Legends", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00072 (Box 5)
    - Typescript headed "Emily Stevens," manuscript annotation, "Appeared in N.Y. World, Sunday, February 12", 1928; MS090.001.005.00073 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript headed "Ellen Terry," article clipping titled "Love of Beauty Keeps Me Young," by Ellen Terry, Psychology, August, 1926; MS090.001.005.00074 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript on the subject of professions pursued alongside the theatrical profession by actors and playwrights, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00075 (Box 5)
    - Typescript headed "Little Theatres in New York: the Triangle Theatre", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00076 (Box 5)
    - Typescript headed "Iris Tree", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00077 (Box 5)
    - Typescript headed "A Theatre of Youth and a Palace of Dreams: the Triangle Theatre", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00078 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript headed "The Vogue of Civility", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00079 (Box 5)
    - Typescript headed "What IS 'The Miracle'?", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00080 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript, three letters (?) headed "B. and B.,", "To a Friend," and "Love", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00081 (Box 5)
    - Two copies of typescript of poem headed "Nantucket," typescript of poem headed "Faces," typed page of epigrams, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00082 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript headed "Charm", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00083 (Box 5)
    - Typescript of two press releases from Rosalie Stewart, Inc., headed "Chrystal Herne Rises to Stardom," and "How I Came to Go on the Stage, by Chrystal Herne, Appearing in 'Craig's Wife,' at the Morosco Theatre,", 1925; MS090.001.005.00084 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript notebook on Sarah Bernhardt, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00085 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript of two drafts for foreword to Bernhardt book, poem marked to appear on page preceding Chapter 1, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00086 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript on Sarah Bernhardt headed "The Shadow Deepens", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00087 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript on Sarah Bernhardt headed "Childhood", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00088 (Box 5)
    - Typescript, two copies of account of Sarah Bernhardt's views on "charm", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00089 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript pages on Sarah Bernhardt's childhood, written on the back of typescript flyers for the Triangle Theatre, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00090 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript, verses from the Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00091 (Box 5)
    - News release, radio station WGBS, announcing reading by AWR from his Bernhardt book, manuscript notes on various past productions on reverse, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00092 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript headed "Sarah and the Critics", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00093 (Box 5)
    - Typescript on Sarah Bernhardt headed "1916 American Tour", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00094 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript and annotated typescript notes on Sarah Bernhardt, typescript of poem titled "La Bernhardt", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00095 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript and annotated typescript pages on Sarah Bernhardt headed "Press Notices", manuscript letter to "J" with manuscript editing requests, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00096 (Box 5)
    - Typescript and annotated typescript pages on Sarah Bernhardt, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00097 (Box 5)
    - Manuscript and annotated typescript, typescript of list of illustrations headed "List of Portraits of Madame Bernhardt", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00098 (Box 5)
    - Typescript pages on Sarah Bernhardt headed "A Bow to Mrs. Grundy", 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00099 (Box 5)
    - Annotated typescript pages on Sarah Bernhardt, 1893 -- 1938; MS090.001.005.00100 (Box 5)